"I try to communicate something
“想要傳達心意…
and self-destruct."
而自我毀滅”
Yes?
是
Your future goals.
你的未來志願
Submit them soon.
快點提交吧
"That day,
“那一天
I confessed my love to you.
我跟小聖告白了
Something came over me."
就這樣情不自禁說出口了”
Ms. Suenaga!
老師！
Ms. Suenaga.
老師
I…
我…
I've fallen in love with you.
我喜歡上老師了
I've fallen for you!
我喜歡上妳了！
I don't
我完全
have a single clue
不知道
about what to do.
該怎麼辦
I thought you hated me.
我以為你討厭我
Thank you.
謝謝你
A student told you he loved you?
學生向妳告白了？
It's that Kuroiwa boy I mentioned before.
就是之前跟妳提過的黑岩同學
The problematic one?
那個有點問題的學生啊？
So he was acting out because he had feelings for you or something?
所以他是因為喜歡妳才這樣叛逆嗎？
Go.
讓開
He wasn't that serious.
不過他並不是那麼認真
He was like "I've fallen in love with you."
“我喜歡上老師了” 像這樣的感覺吧
I think.
我覺得
What is that, a punishment for losing a bet?
是懲罰嗎？打賭輸了被逼著說的嗎？
Maybe.
可能吧
Most likely.
說不定是呢
It's like we're not here.
好像我們不在似的
You got a crush, don't you?
你現在有喜歡的人吧？
It's all over your face.
都寫在臉上了
I'm so right.
我說中了
Did you tell her?
向她告白了嗎？
Go out on a date yet?
有跟她一起出去約會過嗎？
It's not like that.
不是那樣的
I heard you and your mom got in a fight again.
我聽說了，你們母子又吵架啦
I'm a pacifist who hates conflict.
我是討厭吵架的和平主義者
I'm happy to mediate whenever you need.
我隨時都願意當你們的和事佬喔
If she doesn't want to tell me, then I don't care anymore.
既然她什麼都不告訴我，那就算了
-You forgot to say grace. -Thank you for the food.
-你忘了說“我吃飽了” -我吃飽了
-Don't touch-- -It's from Dad.
-等一下，不要碰… -這是爸爸寄來的
Stop! Give that here!
不要開！還給我！
You don't need to read it!
你不用看！
AS HIS FATHER…
（身為他的父親…）
I WANT TO MEET AKIRA
（我想跟阿晶見面）
-And you told Shotaro you can't go? -Yes, for now.
-妳跟勝太郎說妳不能去大阪了吧？ -對，暫時還不行
Will you marry me?
請妳嫁給我
I want to keep teaching here until my students graduate,
我會繼續在這裡執教 直到這屆學生畢業
and get married next year.
然後明年結婚
Then why do you keep eyeing your phone?
既然如此，妳幹嘛一直看手機？
I haven't heard from him since.
在那之後，他就完全沒有聯絡我了
What?
什麼？
Shotaro's bummed!
勝太郎洩氣了吧！
I get it, it's a lot easier when you decide to get married
我懂了 趁著“決定了，結婚吧”的氣勢
get swept up and hitched, and reach the finish line.
立馬登記的話 這樣才能一鼓作氣衝破終點線
If you miss your timing, it really dampens things.
可是一旦錯失了時機，果然會氣餒
-Marriage is momentum. -Really?
-結婚是要一氣呵成的 -是這樣嗎？
Yeah. It was with us.
我們也是這樣
I moved in with my husband three months after meeting him,
我跟老公認識三個月就馬上同居
and then got married at Mach speed.
接著以馬赫般的速度去登記結婚
Yeah, momentum is really important. It's the same for all weddings.
一氣呵成非常重要 大家結婚都是這樣
-I'm not sure it's like that for everyone. -It is.
-應該不是每個人都是這樣的吧 -大家都是
-Is it really? -I'm telling you it is!
-大家都是嗎？ -真的是這樣啦！
-Mach speed. -Mach speed?
-馬赫 -馬赫？
What are you doing next weekend?
下個週末你要做什麼？
Maybe I'll come to Osaka.
我要不要去大阪呢？
She was so happy when I proposed.
求婚時她明明那麼開心
Now she wants to keep teaching.
現在她卻要繼續當老師
Like where did all that excitement go?
害我想說：“奇怪 之前那些雀躍都去哪了？”
You thought she'd quit right away.
你以為她會馬上辭職啊
I, the great and handsome Shotaro Kawai who has everything to offer
像我這樣各方面都無可挑剔的 帥氣的川合勝太郎
asked you to be my wife, so get over to Osaka and take care of me.
讓妳嫁給我 所以馬上來大阪照顧我的起居
You make me sound like a real bastard.
妳怎麼說得我像混蛋似的
You thought she'd just rush over, but she pressed pause instead.
原以為對方立刻跑過來 沒想到卻被說了“等一下”
I'm sure it hurt your pride.
這樣確實很傷自尊心
It's making me a little sad you putting it that way.
妳這樣說害我有點失落
I hate that there might be a sleazy part of me that actually feels that way.
討厭自己心中 搞不好真有一點那種無恥的想法
Yes.
是啊
Speaking of sleazy. That night…
說到無恥，那天晚上…
-Is this an invitation? -I'm just hungry.
-這是邀約嗎？ -我只是餓了
So?
怎樣？
You coming?
要來嗎？
I graciously decline your offer.
請容許我婉拒妳的邀約
I was just offering you dinner out of the kindness of my heart.
我不過出於親切 單純想問你要不要吃晚飯
I'm sorry.
對不起
You acted like I was trying to sleep with you.
你這樣簡直就像我想和你上床似的
I didn't think we should be alone.
兩人獨處還是不太好呀
But I was overthinking it since you have a girlfriend.
是我想太多了 畢竟原口小姐也有女友嘛
Whoa.
哇
Wait, um…
等一下，嗯…
What's happening now?
發生什麼事？
Be careful.
小心點喔
-Up we go. -Sorry.
-來吧 -對不起
I'm a little drunk.
我有點喝醉了
You didn't need to drink that much. Okay.
不能喝就別喝那麼多啦，好啦
We're here.
到了
Okay, put on your shoes.
好了，把鞋子穿好
This isn't funny.
一點也不好笑
Okay.
好
Watch out!
小心！
You're so thin. How do you even fit your organs?
妳真瘦，妳的內臟都裝在哪啊？
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
I got off early, so I came to see you.
我比較早下班，所以就來找妳
-Did he force you to drink? -I didn't do anything.
-他灌妳酒嗎？ -我什麼都沒做
See you.
辛苦啦
They switched to their summer uniforms today.
他們今天開始換穿夏季制服啦
Good morning.
早安
-They look so cool. -Good morning.
-看起來真清爽 -早安
Good morning.
早安
Good morning, Kuroiwa.
黑岩同學，早安
You're supposed to switch to your summer uniform today.
你今天應該要換穿夏季制服的
I didn't notice until I turned the corner.
我到轉角時才發現
It's too late now.
現在已經太遲了
Good morning.
早安
Kuroiwa!
黑岩！
Sorry, thought you were a target.
對不起，還以為是標靶呢
-What's up? -Still the winter uniform?
-妳搞什麼啊？ -還穿著冬季制服嗎？
-You did it on purpose. -No.
-他絕對是故意的 -才不是
-Good morning. -You have makeup on!
-早安 -妳化妝了！
Good morning.
早安
'Morning.
早
-Hello.
-妳好 -你好
Wait, we're covering that in class now.
等一下，這是我們上課時教到的
Any sections you need help with?
有什麼不懂的地方嗎？
Well…
嗯…不懂的地方
Let's see.
我不懂的地方
Why didn't you sit next to me?
為什麼我們之間要隔一個空位？
I've been thinking since then.
在那之後我想過了
About what?
想什麼？
I don't think loving you is enough.
光是喜歡似乎不夠
I…
我…
I want you to fall in love with me
我希望老師
too.
也能喜歡上我
Sorry.
抱歉
That's something I can't do.
這我沒辦法做到
EBIHARA, VERY GOOD JOB.
（海老原同學，寫得很好）
Sorry, I'm visiting my folks this weekend.
抱歉，這個週末要回老家
I haven't told them we're engaged yet.
我還沒通知他們訂婚的事
I'd like to pay my respects too.
我也想跟他們打招呼
I'D LIKE TO PAY MY RESPECTS TOO.
（我也想跟他們打招呼）
Okay!
好啊！
-You can do it! -Keep going!
-加油！
Go, Kuroiwa!
黑岩，加油！
Go, Akira!
衝啊，阿晶！
Kuroiwa's so fast.
真不愧是黑岩
-Go! -Akira!
-衝啊！ -阿晶！
I wanted to see Shotaro.
我想見勝太郎
But why?
為什麼？
KUROIWA
（黑岩）
I'm going to keep my distance for now.
總之先保持距離
Sport's Day is coming up.
馬上就是運動會了
There have been a number of changes this year.
今年有些變動是我們必須注意的
First, no group gymnastics.
首先是取消團體體操
For the obstacle course, we'll place mats under the balance beam
障礙跑的平衡木下面要放墊子
and have students remove hair accessories before they crawl under the net.
參加網子障礙賽的學生 一定要拿掉飾品
-And absolutely no pets allowed. -Pets?
-此外絕對要禁止攜帶寵物進場 -寵物？
And make sure they don't pitch any tents in the schoolyard.
還有不能在校園內搭帳篷
Tents?
帳篷？
We need to be careful.
我們得特別注意呢
This is way more concerning, spreading all these false rumors.
要注意的是這邊 一直散播虛假的流言
We can't delete them fast enough.
真是刪也刪不及
Stay on top of the information management.
資訊管理要做好喔
Yes, ma'am.
是的
HER FIANCE IS THE HEAD OF AN IT COMPANY HE OWNS AN ISLAND IN THE CARRIBEAN
（她的未婚夫是資訊技術公司的主管 在加勒比海有一座小島）
IT'S SO OBVIOUS THAT THIRD YEAR XXXXIWA'S GOT A THING FOR HIJIRI.
（三年級的某岩喜歡小聖 超明顯的）
THREE-EIGHT
（三八超商）
Cut it out already.
不要那麼大聲啦
So that boy was serious.
這麼說，那個學生是認真的囉？
"I want you to fall in love with me."
說什麼“我希望妳喜歡上我”
Very serious.
超認真呀
I don't know how seriously to take it.
我不知道要多認真看待這件事
But I'll be careful.
但我會注意的
I'll keep my distance.
我會保持距離
Try not to agitate him.
儘量不要刺激他
Good idea.
也對
Just remembered, I bought these as they were on sale. Here!
對了，我看到特賣就買回來了，妳看
Thank you, I will gladly accept it.
謝謝妳，我感謝地收下了
What? You're going out?
怎麼了？要出門嗎？
-I'm going to visit Shotaro's parents. -His parents?
-對，我要去拜訪勝太郎的父母 -他的父母？
Just dropping by to pay my respects.
只是去打個招呼而已
You're girlfriend is visiting your parents?
你的女朋友要去拜訪你的父母啊？
How'd you know?
妳怎麼會知道？
Konishi told me.
小西和我說了
That's scary.
好可怕
Huh? Word really gets around fast.
咦？這麼快就傳出去啦
-I'll keep to myself then. -I know your plan.
-我以後什麼都不說了 -我知道你打什麼注意
You're going to use your parents to pressure her to come to Osaka,
借著跟父母見面說服她 讓她順從你的意思來大阪
so she'll be in reach, you sly tactician.
都是為了讓她待在你身邊 你這個狡猾的戰術家
I can only imagine what you think of me.
我在原口小姐心裡 究竟是什麼樣的人啊？
Just a little neighborly warning.
身為鄰居給你個忠告
-Yes? -Families can be tricky.
-是 -家庭關係很難搞
My married friends all have issues with their in-laws.
我的已婚朋友 全都會抱怨跟公婆的問題
The sooner the families meet, the better.
你還是儘快讓雙方家長見面比較好吧
I'll take my consultation fee now.
好，請付我顧問費
I believe I took care of you when you got blackout drunk.
上次妳喝個爛醉，我還幫了妳吧？
Not to mention I got knocked down for my trouble.
而且最後還被推倒在地
She gets jealous easily.
她很容易吃醋
-I have tomorrow's presentation materials. -Thanks.
-明天要發表的資料準備好了 -謝謝
I know it's sudden but would you like to invite your parents?
我知道很唐突 但要請妳爸媽也一起來嗎？
What?
嗯？
Your parents?
妳的爸媽？
I asked my folks, and they invited them to dinner.
我問了我的父母 他們說要請妳的父母一起吃晚餐
-Wait, my parents are going too? -Their first meeting?
-等一下，我爸媽也要去嗎？ -雙方家長初次會面？
-Is it too short notice? -Yes!
-是不是太倉促了？ -是啊！
What will you do? You need to change!
怎麼辦？妳得快換衣服！
First, I'll call my…
我先打電話回家
-Hey Mom, can you make it? -Your hair.
-喂，媽媽，可以嗎？ -妳的頭髮
-Let's put your hair up. -Ow!
-頭髮捲起來 -好痛！
Have a nice day.
我先走了
They're out? Why now?
要退出？為什麼現在才說？
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
The manufacturers are backing out of the India deal.
製造商說要退出印度的專案
-What? -Were the price terms too harsh?
-什麼？ -是價格條件太嚴苛嗎？
Or they got poached?
還是跑去別家了？
It's okay, I will convince them.
沒事，我會立刻 安排會議並說服他們的
-Konishi, call the chief! -Yes, ma'am!
-小西，打電話給部長！ -是的！
Send this to Vietnam and India.
這個，也寄給越南跟印度那邊
We're counting on you.
拜託你了
You can't make it?
你不能來？
Sorry, there's a work emergency.
對不起，工作突然出了問題
I can't get out of it. Sorry could you go without me.
我一時無法脫身 抱歉，妳一個人陪他們吧
What? Just me and our parents?
什麼？我單獨去見雙方父母嗎？
I'm really sorry! I'll call you later!
真的很抱歉，我晚點再打給妳
Wai--
等…
What?
什麼？
-Kawai, good work on your day off. -What?
-川合，假日出勤辛苦了 -嗯？
You may go. Make sure to make it up.
記得要補假，你可以走了
But we're in a crisis!
可是現在這個危機！
This is Konishi's account, and the presentation is tomorrow.
這家廠商是小西負責的 而且明天就要發表
To be blunt, you being here would change nothing.
說實話，無論有沒有你都沒差
-Maybe, but there's a chance I-- -Are you thick?
-也許是這樣沒錯，但我也許能… -你聽不懂嗎？
I'm saying go meet each other's families.
今天你得和雙方父母要見面
Pulling out last minute will impact their faith in you.
臨時取消會失去信用
And again, you being here will change nothing.
而且我再說一次 有沒有你在都無所謂
That's a bit hurtful.
這樣有點傷人啊
But if someone asks you where you went,
但待會假如有人問起你去了哪
I'll probably have to act angry.
我可能會說：“什麼？他溜走了？” 然後假裝上司生氣的樣子
-Just a heads up. -I won't go then!
-提醒你一聲 -那我就不去了！
I'll be angry now if you don't!
你不去的話，我現在就會生氣！
Thank you!
謝謝妳！
Hijiri!
聖！
You made it!
趕上了！
-I'm sorry this was so sudden. -Do you think this outfit is okay?
-對不起，這麼倉促 -穿這樣可以嗎？
When I pulled it out, it was so wrinkled.
我把衣服拿出來時皺巴巴的
I frantically ironed it.
還慌慌張張地熨平
You're taking this too seriously.
妳太緊張啦
We're not going to some mansion.
又不是要去拜訪什麼大豪宅
-Right? -Yeah.
-是嗎？ -是啊
Oh, my…
天啊…
-What an impressive house. -It really is.
-好壯觀的屋子啊 -真的很壯觀
-I'm so sorry for the sudden invitation. -Alright!
-突然邀約真是抱歉 -好了！
-And Shotaro can't even make it. -I'm sorry about this.
-結果勝太郎自己居然不能來 -真是不好意思
-We hate to intrude. -Thank you for your hospitality.
-我們才不好意思，打擾了 -謝謝妳的招待
-Honey! -Sorry.
-老公！ -對不起
Please excuse me.
我接一下
-Yes? How did it go? -Please eat.
-好的，怎麼樣？ -請吃吧
He must be busy.
他工作一定很忙
He works sales at an advertising firm.
他在一家廣告公司從事銷售工作
I'm just your typical office worker.
我只是個普通上班族
Why did you want to be a teacher, Hijiri?
聖為什麼想當老師呢？
It was my dream as a child.
這是我從小的夢想
-She copied her friend. -What?
-是學朋友的啦 -咦？
Remember Miyu from the neighborhood?
還記得我們家附近的美由嗎？
She said she wanted to be a teacher, and you said me too.
她說未來想當老師 妳就說“我也要”
No, I have my own reason.
不是啦，我有自己的理由
I saw a school documentary that moved me,
我在電視上看到學校紀錄片深受感動
and the students I met through student teaching were so wonderful.
還有教育實習時認識的學生 全都是很乖的孩子
I'm sorry about that!
真是不好意思！
So, why did you want to become a teacher, Hijiri?
那聖為什麼想當老師？
She copied her friend.
是學朋友的啦
Ow!
痛！
-What? -Have some beer.
-什麼？ -喝啤酒吧
Here you go.
請享用吧
Thank you very much.
謝謝
So the wedding will be next year?
那婚禮訂在明年嗎？
Yes, I think so.
是的，目前是這麼想
You'll be moving to Osaka after your class graduates, right?
等現在的學生畢業之後 妳就會去大阪，是吧？
We're discussing it.
我們還在討論
-Let me see your bowl. -Thank you.
-請把碗給我 -謝謝
Shotaro was assigned to Osaka for two years.
勝太郎被調去大阪兩年
So I either go there for one year, or keep teaching at my current school.
所以我要明年去大阪一年 還是繼續待在現在的學校當老師
We can get married first and think about our options later.
總之可以先結婚後再慢慢考慮
What are you talking about?
妳在說什麼呢？
You should live together once married.
結婚之後就要一起生活啊
But I want to build my teaching experience.
但我想累積教學經驗
-So career-minded! -It's nothing.
-事業心真強！ -哪裡
But Shotaro works for a trading company.
不過勝太郎是在貿易公司上班
He'll probably be assigned overseas someday.
未來也可能會被調派國外
Sooner or later, your job…
遲早妳的工作也…
Yes, you should quit.
對呀，辭掉吧
-More beer? -Thank you.
-還要啤酒嗎？ -謝謝
Actually, how about some wine instead? I've got a great one.
喝葡萄酒怎麼樣？ 我有一瓶很好喝的酒
What made you fall for Shotaro?
聖為什麼選擇勝太郎？
Back in college…
讀大學時…
as part of my outdoor activities group we went hiking up a mountain.
我參加了戶外社團 然後我們一起去登山
But I was inexperienced and fell behind.
可是我沒有登山經驗 很快就落後大家
It was tough.
爬得很辛苦
But there was always a green backpack in front of me.
可是前面一直有個綠色的背包
Everyone had gone ahead, but it was always there in front of me.
明明大家都爬很遠了 但是它卻始終在我前面
Like a guide.
像個嚮導似的
Shotaro has always been my goal.
勝太郎是我的目標
He always gives me inspiration and the energy to go forward.
他總是為我打氣 以及給我前進的動力
I know that everything will be okay if I follow him.
讓我知道只要跟著他走就沒問題了
I want to be a wife worthy of him.
我想成為配得上他的太太
Not just support him,
並不只是扶持他
but be someone who can stand alongside him.
未來有一天想跟他並肩而行
That's how I'd like us to be.
我想跟他成為這樣的夫妻
That's why it's my goal right now to become a great teacher.
所以成為獨當一面的老師 是我現在的目標
I'm sorry for being so selfish.
這麼任性真是抱歉
Well, shoot.
哪裡哪裡，真傷腦筋
I'm sorry to say my son isn't that special!
我兒子他才沒這麼出眾呢！
Come on, eat up! You're still young.
聖快吃吧！妳還年輕啊
Thank you.
謝謝
KUROIWA, GOOD JOB.
（黑岩同學，你寫得很好）
Are you getting married?
老師，你們要結婚了嗎？
-It was four against one. -Yeah.
-四對一喔 -是啊
The first time our parents are meeting, and I'm suddenly on my own!
雙方家長初次見面，我就孤身一人
The silence was so awkward!
沈默的氣氛真的太尷尬了！
Stop trying to deflect!
你別想蒙混過關！
I'm not that special.
我沒有那麼出眾
I'm happy you called me your goal.
雖然聽妳說我是妳的目標 我覺得很高興
But I'm not that special.
但我沒那麼出眾
I'm so boring.
我個性也不有趣
Someone in Osaka told me I was boring.
大阪有同事說我是個無趣的人
That's harsh.
真嚴格啊
If tired I go to bed at 8:00 p.m., plus I watch porn.
有時累了八點就去睡覺了 而且還看色情影片
You do? You watch porn?
你有？你看色情影片？
-Hmm?
-嗯？
Even when there was a work emergency,
即使工作上出了問題
Ms. Haraguchi was like "we don't need you, get out of here already!"
可是原口小姐卻說 “不需要你啦，趕快走！”
I'm glad you made it.
我很高興你來了
I don't deserve such high praise.
妳還願意稱讚這樣的我
I will cherish you.
我一定會好好珍惜妳
I guess we shouldn't rush things.
我想我們不應該操之過急
You should do what you want.
妳就照妳的想法去做吧
When we get married, when we start living together,
何時要結婚，何時要一起生活
your career path,
妳的職業道路
you can decide.
隨妳的意思去做
I will be waiting.
我會等妳
-The pose of confidence. -What the heck is that?
-信心滿滿的姿勢 -什麼啊？
-Was it funny? -Yeah, maybe I'll try it.
-有趣吧？ -很有趣，我也想試試
-Next time. -What? Do it now.
-下次吧 -什麼？現在做一次吧
He went back to Osaka?
他回大阪了嗎？
He made his last train.
嗯，他趕上了最後一班車
Huh? The light won't turn on.
奇怪，燈不會亮
What a shabby lifestyle.
妳真是過著簡陋的生活啊
So sorry.
很抱歉
I can't believe how nice Shotaro's parents' home was.
真不敢相信 勝太郎的老家原來這麼豪華
We could never invite them over to our place.
我們家根本不敢邀請對方來
But you are so fortunate.
不過妳真幸運啊
You should thank your lucky stars.
要好好感謝神明
I swear, you'll never find anyone
我敢說妳這輩子都不可能再遇到
that amazing ever again.
那麼出色的人了
I know that.
我知道啦
But it's good to know you're working hard being a teacher.
不過很好啊，妳也很努力當老師呢
I can't reach. Whoops.
摸不到，哎呀
So how are your students?
妳的學生怎麼樣？
Well, we're finally settling in, so we're on our way I'd say.
終於開始習慣了 正在正確的軌道上吧
You have any troublemakers?
有問題學生嗎？
I suppose there's one student I'm worried about.
有一個令我很在意的學生
What are they like?
什麼樣的孩子？
Good grades, good athlete,
成績很好，運動神經也很好
but they're unsure of their future.
可是卻對未來很迷惘
And get strangely aggressive sometimes.
有時會特別有攻擊性
But then tells me they love a poem.
可是又會說他喜歡一首詩
Welcome Rain on a Spring Night.
《春夜喜雨》
They memorized the poem I taught.
他們記得我教的詩
Made me glad I became a teacher.
讓我覺得能成為老師實在是太好了
Is that right?
是嗎？
When I lost all my confidence and was about to give up, they saved me…
當我失去自信想要放棄時 學生拯救了我…
I'm glad to hear it's fulfilling.
太好了，很有成就感呢
-I'll come visit soon. -Okay.
-下次找時間去看看妳吧 -好啊
Thanks for today. Good night.
今天謝謝你們，晚安
Who's in love?
誰談戀愛了？
Your boy Akira.
妳的阿晶啊
I noticed he was acting weird lately. That's when I realized.
總覺得他最近好像怪怪的 我就突然想到了
Acting weird?
感覺怪怪的？
Like how?
比如呢？
He's always spacing out.
他總是心不在焉的樣子
He's been spacing out most of his life.
他大半輩子都是在發呆啊
When he was a kid, he'd always wear his shirt backwards.
小時候總是把衣服前後穿反
Well, lately he's always listening to music on his own.
最近常看到他一個人在聽音樂
Do some work.
快工作
18, 19, 20, 21,
18、19、20、21
22, 23!
22、23！
What're you doing, Kokonoe!
九重，你在幹嘛！
Your skirts distracted me!
我很在意妳們的裙子啦！
We have pants under!
我們裡面有穿褲子啦！
-Come on, stop that. -You shattered my dreams!
-不要這樣啦 -幹嘛打破我的夢想！
-Idiot. -Cut it out, Kokonoe!
-笨蛋 -九重同學別說了！
Kuroiwa!
黑岩！
Ebihara, can you take over for me?
海老原同學，可以換你來拉嗎？
Sure thing.
好的
-Here. -We're going again?
-來 -再一次？
-Good luck, everyone! -You're leaving?
-大家加油喔！ -老師要回去了嗎？
-Sorry. -Now I've lost motivation.
-對不起 -我失去幹勁了啦
-Where you going? -Home. I'm ditching.
-你要去哪裡？ -回家，我要早退了
What about your bag? Kuroiwa!
你的書包呢？黑岩！
He seems irritated, and his mind is elsewhere.
他看起來毛毛躁躁又心不在焉
-I was like that once. -When?
-我以前也曾那樣 -什麼時候？
Back when you were a delinquent?
當混混的時候嗎？
-Or when you were in that comedic band? -Listen, it was a Hawaiian band.
-跟朋友組搞笑樂團的時候嗎？ -妳給我聽好，那是夏威夷樂團啦
I've been watching Akira since he was a kid.
我看著阿晶從小長大
-I can tell that something's off. -I'm sure he has a crush or two.
-所以我知道他最近有點奇怪 -應該是有暗戀的女生吧
He's already 15.
他都十五歲了
Yes, he's 15.
是啊，他十五歲了
I hate to tell you, but being in love at 15
我不想這麼說，但十五歲的戀愛
takes a physical and mental toll.
可是很折磨身體和心靈的
It's not just finding a girl cute.
可不只是單純覺得女生很可愛而已
You want to see them, touch them, and touch them some more!
而是想見對方，想摸對方 可以的話想更進一步！
Your head is filled with these fantasies and desires.
這種妄想跟欲望充斥著腦袋
That's what being in love at 15 is. Love in the prime of youth!
這就是十五歲的戀愛 正值青春期的戀愛！
Love, huh?
戀愛啊？
Here you go.
給你
Thanks.
謝謝
-Where's your mom? -In the warehouse.
-你媽呢？ -在倉庫
I see.
哦
It's an all Asian décor. It's nice.
裝潢是亞洲風啊，真有品味
What?
什麼？
You have a cold or something? Dosage is hard.
你感冒嗎？ 不知道該吃多少劑量的藥吧
We're still 14, but we're almost 15.
我們還只是十四歲，但就快要十五了
It's hard to gauge if we can take the adult dosage.
不知道是不是可以服用 跟大人相同的劑量了
I guess you already turned 15 in April.
你四月生日時就十五歲了吧
-Here. -What did you come here for?
-給你 -妳到底來幹嘛？
You should really forget about Suenaga.
你應該忘掉末永
I mean, it's partly her fault for being so friendly.
我是說 也是她不對啦，一副裝親切的樣子
-Right? -Go home.
-對吧？ -回去
She has a fiancé.
她有未婚夫喔
You're just going to get hurt.
你只會受到傷害罷了
-And this is an important-- -Enough!
-而且現在是我們很重要… -夠了！
-Go home. -Fine, I was going to!
-回去 -我走，不用你說我也會走！
But at the very least,
但是至少…
unlike Suenaga, I came here prepared to get a little hurt.
我跟末永不一樣 我來之前已經做好多少會傷心的覺悟
We have a visitor?
有客人嗎？
Oh, if it isn't Runa!
哦，是瑠奈啊！
What are you two…?
你們兩個…
-Wait, I see… -No, we're not.
-等一下，我… -不，不是那樣的
-Really? -I have to go! We're not!
-真的嗎？ -我得走了！不是那樣的！
That's why you two… Wait, Runa!
所以你們兩個…等一下，瑠奈！
Akira.
阿晶
I'm just going to ask, how should I be taking this?
我只想知道 我應該怎麼理解這個情況？
You know, just to prepare myself.
我得做好心理準備啊
Am I ready for this?
我做好心理準備了嗎？
She
她
creeps me out.
真噁心
About as much as me.
像我一樣
What?
什麼？
KOBOSHI JUNIOR HIGH SPORTS DAY
（子星中學運動會）
Please put your valuables in this bag.
請把貴重物品放到這個袋子裡
-Here you go. -Thank you.
-給妳 -謝謝
Okay, thank you. Thank you.
好的，謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝
I'll take it, it's cute.
很可愛啊，就給我吧
Careful not to get heat stroke. Make sure you drink plenty of fluids.
大家要小心中暑，一定要多喝水
Also, did you write your names on your headbands?
還有都在頭帶上寫好名字了嗎？
-Ugh, just look at them. -Please check.
-哎，看他們，可惡 -請檢查
What is this, a teen drama?
搞什麼青春劇啊？
Maybe I'll also find someone to…
可能我也會找個人…
Is there a point to it?
那有什麼意義？
You think you're so cool! Must be nice!
你這個傢伙因為自己很酷吧！ 很爽吧！
-You got so many girls wanting to trade. -I don't care!
-大把女生都要跟你交換 -我不在乎啦！
If you can't trade with anyone…
如果你都不跟別人交換的話…
Okay, let's go.
好了，要走囉
-Give it! -No!
-拿來 -不要啦！
What the hell?
幹嘛啦？
Come on, we're heading out.
快點，要走了
-Runachi, you got your eye on Kuroiwa's? -Not really.
-瑠奈，妳想要黑岩的頭帶嗎？ -才沒有
You could treasure it forever.
可以珍藏一輩子喔
Watch out!
小心！
Everyone have everything?
東西都帶齊了嗎？
Three, two, one!
三、二、一！
Go!
衝啊！
You can do it!
加油！
So girly.
女人味
I can smell it.
我能聞到啊
You mean my perfume or cleanser?
妳是說 我的香水還是洗衣精的味道嗎？
Not from you, but those girls over there are overflowing with it.
我不是說妳 是那些女生到處都充滿了女人味
What's the goal of Sport's Day?
運動會的宗旨是什麼？
Demonstrate their daily achievements, deepen their ability for group action
展現日常的成果 加強團體行動的連結
and carry on school tradition.
傳承校風傳統
Yet they've forgotten its true purpose,
但她們都忘記了原本的意義
just screaming and causing a ruckus.
只在那邊興奮尖叫亂成一團
But it feels a little nostalgic.
不過令人有點懷念
-Nostalgic? -Yes.
-懷念？ -是的
Makes me realize that we acted like that too.
我自己以前也是像那樣興奮大叫吧
I feel like I'm transported back to when I was a student.
就像回到了學生時代
You still think that way.
妳果然還會這麼想
When you reach my age, you feel just the opposite.
到了我這年紀就完全相反
I fully realize that I'll never feel that young ever again.
我深深感知自己早已沒有那種青春了
We must protect them
我們一定要拼命
at all cost.
守護他們
-Team Peach wins! -Yes.
-桃子組獲勝！ -是
Himena in a yellow and blue hat is looking for her mother.
戴著黃藍色帽子的 姬愛小朋友在找媽媽
If you know her, please come by the main tent.
母親聽到後，請到總部帳篷
Ms. Suenaga!
老師！
I'm sorry about before.
上次真是不好意思
-Akira must be a handful. -It's nothing.
-阿晶惹了很多麻煩 -沒事
Are you off work?
今天不用工作嗎？
I do my best to make it to events like these.
這類活動能來的話，我都會儘量參加
-You can tell how much they've grown. -Start when I say get set, go!
-可以看到他們的成長 -聽我說“準備好”就開始！
Even now.
現在也是
Kuroiwa!
黑岩！
Give me that.
你那個給我
-This? -Yeah.
-這個？ -是
It'll help motivate me to run the final relay faster.
會鼓勵我在最後一場接力賽跑快些
So…
所以…
Trade with mine.
和我交換吧
I've been worried about Akira's recent erratic behavior,
阿晶最近行為很古怪 所以我有些擔心
then I see they're so close.
沒想到不知不覺就談戀愛了
First loves can be so cute.
青澀的初戀真是可愛
Exchanging headbands with your crush seems to be popular.
現在好像流行跟喜歡的人交換頭帶
But seeing him suddenly get a crush,
不過突然看到他有喜歡的對象了
I realize he'll soon start dating and then get married,
我就會想到 他有一天會交女朋友然後結婚
and before too long will be leaving the nest.
像這樣慢慢離開父母
Yes, one day.
是啊，總有一天
What kind of adult will he become?
不知道他會成為什麼樣的大人？
As long as he can keep laughing and he's happy,
只要他能面帶笑容並且快樂地生活
that's all that matters.
我就別無所求了
I hope I can help as his teacher.
希望我能以老師的身份幫助他
Sincerely.
真心地這麼想
That's reassuring, Ms. Suenaga.
那我就放心了，老師
Thank you.
是的
Yuko Kawashima.
川嶋夕子同學
Kosuke Tsubota.
坪田康佑同學
Here you go.
來
-Ms. Suenaga. -Here.
-老師 -來
Okay, all second years gather up for the ball rolling event!
好的，全體二年級生集合 開始滾球專案！
Gather round!
過來集合！
The next event will be the second year girls'…
下個項目是二年級的女子…
Yamamoto from Class 3-2…
三年二班的山本同學…
What is this? You need to stop messing around.
你在做什麼？你別胡鬧了
Why?
為什麼？
Why are you actively avoiding looking at or talking to me?
為什麼回避我眼神，不跟我說話？
Is it because I said I liked you?
是因為我說了我喜歡妳嗎？
Of course not.
當然不是
It may not look it, but I'm pretty busy. You're overly concerned.
別看我這樣 其實我很忙的，你想太多了
Now come on, the relay is next.
該走了，下個項目就是接力了吧
Once again, group A for the relay semi-finals, please come to the gate.
再次重複，A組接力半決賽請進場
Don't treat me like a kid.
別把我當小孩！
Why are you running away?
為什麼要躲著我？
Let me be clear then.
那我就明說了
I don't appreciate this.
我不想這樣
So stop.
別再這樣子了
I will root for you as your teacher.
我會以老師的身分替你加油
Nothing more, nothing less.
除此之外沒有其他感情
So please stop.
所以別再這樣了
What is this?
怎麼了？
It's not right.
太奇怪了
I thought it was supposed to be something special.
我以為這應該是很美好的事
Love.
戀愛
And they're off!
他們起跑了！
Red team is in the lead…
紅隊暫時領先…
Ms. Haraguchi is being taken off?
原口小姐要被調走？
The India project leader is a hard ass.
印度專案負責人是個硬骨頭
But why?
為什麼？
That mistake of ours…
我們出的錯…
It was a setup from the beginning.
從一開始就是個圈套
You know the rumors with her and the boss.
你也知道她跟社長之間的謠言
It's office politics.
這就是辦公室政治
No…
怎麼會…
-Hey! -We received a phone call.
-喂！ -我們接到電話
They'd like another meeting when they're back next month.
下個月他們會來日本開會
-What? -We need Ms. Haraguchi.
-做什麼？ -我們需要原口小姐
I'm sorry. I know it's not my place to say this.
對不起，我也許沒資格插嘴
-But she's needed. -Kawai.
-但是我們需要她 -川合
She's close with the locals, and being the boss's mistress is just a rumor.
她和當地很熟 而且社長情婦的事也都是謠言罷了
-She has someone-- -Our presentation was a success.
-她已經有戀人了… -提案通過了
-What? -They accepted the deal.
-什麼？ -生意談成了
I was just telling the chief.
我剛剛跟部長彙報
Is that right?
是這樣嗎？
What's this about the boss's what?
跟社長的那些事是指什麼？
Well, that's…
啊，那是…
Is an explanation required?
有需要解釋嗎？
Well, I heard what I heard.
我都聽到了，我就想知道啊
-My wing's broken. -What?
-我的翅膀斷了 -嗯？
I can't believe I had to tell him
我竟然被逼著要向他解釋
that there was a rumor about me and the boss.
關於我和社長之間的傳言
-My wing's broken. -You mean spirit?
-翅膀都被折斷了 -妳是說內心感到挫折啊？
-Kawai. -Yes?
-川合 -是
-You get caught by the dumbest things. -I'm sorry.
-你總是在意一些愚蠢的點啊 -對不起
Do you get that my spirit and wing is broken
你知道我的心靈和翅膀都折斷了
because you decided to butt in?
就是因為你擅自決定插嘴嗎？
I'm sorry!
對不起！
I couldn't help myself after I heard from Konishi that you were being taken off.
我聽到小西說 妳要被調出計畫案就忍不住了
I'm going to have to throttle Konishi.
真想掐死他
But it's better now that the rumor was put to rest.
不過這樣不好嗎？ 這樣就不會有莫名的謠言了
-What? -Might as well go out with me.
-這是？ -跟我約會
What?
什麼？
We're down to the final event.
終於到了最後的競技項目
It will be the school-wide team relay!
全校大隊接力賽！
We're counting on you, Anchor!
拜託妳啦，最後一棒！
Huh? Kuroiwa?
咦？黑岩呢？
You got this!
加油！
Ms. Suenaga! Kuroiwa's missing!
末永老師！黑岩不見了！
My keys.
鑰匙
Don't hang up, you idiot.
別掛電話啊，這個笨蛋
I managed to reach him.
剛才聯絡到他了
He went home because he wasn't feeling well.
他說身體不舒服先回家了
But then he felt better and decided to go out.
不過現在恢復了，所以他已經出門了
Did he mention where?
他有說要去哪裡嗎？
That's when he hung up.
他沒說就掛了
I'm so sorry for causing such a commotion!
讓大家擔心真的非常抱歉！
Please contact us if anything happens.
如果有消息的話，請馬上通知我們
Yes, I'll be sure to give him a proper scolding later.
是，晚點我會好好罵他一頓
-I'm so sorry. -Take care now.
-真的非常抱歉 -辛苦了
-Please take care now.
-真的很抱歉 -回去小心喔
I'm so sorry.
真的很抱歉
I think that wraps things up on our end.
那之後就沒我們的事了
I can't believe he went home right before the relay.
不過居然在接力賽之前回去
He needs to face consequences!
他應該受點教訓！
Kuroiwa has caused a little too much trouble lately.
最近黑岩同學惹出的事有點多呢
Any reason he might be acting out?
妳知道是什麼原因嗎？
Now come on, the relay is next.
該走了，下個項目就是接力了吧
I don't appreciate this.
我不想這樣
So stop.
別再這樣子了
He's your student.
他是妳的學生
Please work on understanding what is on his mind right now,
妳要努力去瞭解 現在黑岩同學到底在想什麼
or what matters might be troubling him.
還是內心有什麼煩惱
Yes, ma'am.
是
I'm exhausted!
累死人了！
All right, let's got to Miyoshiya.
我們走吧，去三好屋
Not the boxed lunch place, the place by the beach.
不是賣便當的那家喔，是海邊的
-What about Ms. Shioya? -She went home.
-鹽谷老師呢？ -她回家了
She had to put together something for the BOE.
她說還要整理教育委員會的資料
-I'll go park my car somewhere first. -Okay.
-我先去停好車 -好的
We can head there now.
我們現在直接過去了
Everyone wants to put a label on me.
每個人都愛給我貼標籤
Women will just get married and quit right away!
反正女人馬上就要結婚然後辭職！
Why tennis?
為什麼要打網球？
If they don't, they're mistresses or old maids.
剩下的女人不是搞婚外情 就是老姑婆
Or mentally unstable!
還是精神不穩定！
Damn it.
可惡
Or others close themselves off when they find out I have a girlfriend.
甚至在知道我有女友之後 就會有人突然跟我斷絕往來
But you didn't change.
可是你卻沒變
Why not?
為什麼？
Who knows.
不知道
Because you're you?
因為妳是原口小姐吧？
What's that mean?
什麼意思？
-Huddle up. -Okay.
-集合 -好
Hijiri called you her goal?
小聖說你是她的目標嗎？
Uh, yes.
嗯，是的
You haven't realized a goal is something that feels distant?
你不覺得目標 是一種遙遠的存在嗎？
There's a chance she's feeling distant from you.
也許是她覺得有距離感
Living long distance, you start drifting apart,
分隔兩地的生活開始出現分歧
unable to be honest.
無法坦誠相待
Unable to be vulnerable.
無法示弱
You gradually become strangers.
因此你們漸漸地成為陌生人
Be careful, Kawai.
小心點，川合
So I guess being long-distance isn't going to work, huh?
所以遠距離戀愛果然不行嗎？
If you're worried, start making moves!
擔心的話就快點行動！
Damn it!
可惡！
I thought I returned that one!
還以為可以反擊呢！
It wasn't bad.
不錯喔
What?
嗯？
Kuroiwa, you okay?
黑岩同學，你還好嗎？
Did you fall?
你摔下來了嗎？
Did you hit your head?
你有撞到頭嗎？
Your leg!
你的腳！
Can you stand?
能站起來嗎？
Does it hurt?
很痛嗎？
Ms. Suenaga.
老師
Please don't come to hate me.
請不要討厭我
Kuroiwa.
黑岩同學
Your bone is digging into me. It hurts.
黑岩同學，你的骨頭卡得我很痛
Come on, we need to patch you up, okay?
我得幫你處理腳的傷口，好嗎？
And if someone sees us--
而且在這種地方會被人看到…
I don't care if anyone sees us.
我無所謂，被誰看到都沒關係
You need to calm down.
等一下，你冷靜一點
I'm going home.
我回去了
Hold on.
等一下
You think your mom's still working?
你媽還在工作嗎？
I'll try calling her again.
我等一下再試試打給她
So you like that song, Ms. Suenaga?
老師，妳喜歡那首歌嗎？
This?
這個嗎？
It's not mine, it's his.
這不是我的，是男友的
I wasn't joking when I said it.
我說那句話不是在捉弄妳
I love you.
我喜歡老師
So you can try to twist reality all you want and try to avoid this situation,
所以妳可以盡情扭曲現實 試圖逃避這種情況
but it's just who I am.
但我就是這樣的人
-Is that the last of it, boss? -Yeah!
-社長，這是最後一個嗎？ -是的！
She's not answering. What should I do?
她沒接，怎麼辦？
Can I take you home?
你要回家嗎？
I don't have a key.
我沒鑰匙
Oh right, you mentioned that.
對喔，你說過了
We need to treat your leg too.
腳也得擦藥才行
How about the hospital?
要去醫院嗎？
No, I'm okay.
不用，我沒事
He's your student.
他是妳的學生
Okay, I'll take you to my place to treat you until I reach your mom.
總之，在聯絡上你媽媽前 先到我家擦藥吧
I forgot the light was out.
對了，我忘記燈泡燒壞了
Come in.
請進
Wash your wound and wait for me.
先清洗傷口等我
Here.
來
Does it hurt?
會痛嗎？
I'm okay.
我沒事
Can I ask you something?
我可以問妳一件事嗎？
Why are you…
為什麼妳要…
Why are you helping me?
為什麼妳要幫我？
Going this far.
做到這個程度
You're hurt, I'm doing what any teacher would do.
你受傷了 我只是做身為教師應該做的事
Is that all?
只是因為這樣嗎？
Am I…
我剛才…
being too sensitive?
想太多而會錯意了嗎？
This isn't good.
這樣下去不行
Are you okay now?
你現在還好嗎？
Kuroiwa.
黑岩同學
Listen,
聽著
I have someone I love.
我有喜歡的人
So…
所以…
Could I borrow some money?
我可以借一點錢嗎？
I'd like to get something from the store downstairs.
我想去樓下超商買點什麼
Right, you must be hungry. I'll get you a drink.
你肚子餓了吧，想不想也喝點什麼？
No, I'll go. I'm worried you might buy something weird.
我去吧，我怕妳買些奇怪的東西
-But your leg. -I'm okay.
-但你的腳 -我沒事
Do you need anything?
要幫妳買什麼嗎？
No, I'm okay.
我不用了
The person you are trying to reach is not available.
您現在撥打的電話暫時無人接聽
Kuroiwa, I'll just drive you back--
黑岩同學，我還是送你回…
I bring gifts.
這是伴手禮
-Thank you. -Sorry for the surprise.
-謝謝你 -抱歉，嚇了妳一跳
I had the urge to come see you.
我突然很想見妳
Found something.
找到了
It's Akira's crush.
阿晶喜歡的人
Really?
真的？
Isn't this Hijiri his…?
這個小聖不是他的…
It can't be.
怎麼可能？
Ms. Suenaga?
老師？
Have you done anything to warrant these torrid rumors?
妳有沒有做會傳出這種謠言的事？
Kuroiwa's got a girlfriend!
黑岩交到女友了！
-It's none of your business! -Of course it's my business!
-跟老師沒關係！ -怎麼可能跟我沒關係？
You can't erase your feelings for someone.
喜歡的心是絕對無法忘記的
It's impossible.
不可能
Subtitle translation by: Zensho Yamamoto
字幕翻譯：楊易